[
  {
    "number": 1,
    "question": "It is being given that 2\u00b3\u00b2 is completely divisible by a whole number. Which of the following numbers is completely divisible by this number?",
    "options": ["2\u00b9\u2076 + 1", "2\u00b9\u2076 - 1", "7 × 2\u00b2\u00b3", "2\u2079\u2076 + 1"],
    "answer": "2\u00b9\u2076 - 1"
  },
  {
    "number": 2,
    "question": "The greatest number of four digit which is divisible by 15, 25, 40 and 75 is:",
    "options": ["9000", "9400", "9600", "9800"],
    "answer": "9000"
  },
  {
    "number": 3,
    "question": "Two bus tickets from city A to B and three tickets from city A to C costs Rs. 90 but three tickets from city A to B and two tickets from city A to C costs Rs. 85. What are the fares for cities B and C from A?",
    "options": ["Rs. 10, Rs. 20", "Rs. 15, Rs. 20", "Rs. 15, Rs. 14", "Rs. 20, Rs. 10"],
    "answer": "Rs. 15, Rs. 14"
  },
  {
    "number": 4,
    "question": "14, 28, 20, 40, 32, 64, What number should come next?",
    "options": ["52", "128", "96", "56"],
    "answer": "56"
  },
  {
    "number": 5,
    "question": "A woman says \"if you reverse my own age the figure represents my husband's age, he is of course senior to me and the difference between our ages is one-eleventh of their sum\". The woman's age is:",
    "options": ["24 years", "34 years", "45 years", "35 years"],
    "answer": "45 years"
  },
  {
    "number": 6,
    "question": "A waiter's salary consists of his salary and tips. During one week his tips were 5/4 of his salary. What fraction of his income came from tips?",
    "options": ["4/9", "5/4", "5/8", "5/9"],
    "answer": "5/9"
  },
  {
    "number": 7,
    "question": "A man completes a journey in 10 hours. He travels first half of the journey at the rate of 21 km/hr and second half at the rate of 24 km/hr. Find the total journey in km:",
    "options": ["220 km", "224 km", "230 km", "234 km"],
    "answer": "224 km"
  },
  {
    "number": 8,
    "question": "A and B can complete a work in 15 days and 10 days respectively. They started doing the work together but after 2 days B had to leave and A alone completed the remaining work. How many days more will A take to finish the work?",
    "options": ["10", "8", "12", "15"],
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "number": 9,
    "question": "The length of the bridge, which a train 130 meters long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds is:",
    "options": ["200", "225", "245", "250"],
    "answer": "245"
  },
  {
    "number": 10,
    "question": "If one third of one fourth of a number is 15, then four tenth of that number is:",
    "options": ["72", "70", "60", "62"],
    "answer": "72"
  },
  {
    "number": 11,
    "question": "The angle between the minute hand and the hour hand of a clock when the time is 4:20 is:",
    "options": ["0°", "10°", "5º", "20°"],
    "answer": "10°"
  },
  {
    "number": 12,
    "question": "The curved surface area of a cylindrical pillar is 264 m² and its volume is 924 m³. Find the ratio of its diameter to its height:",
    "options": ["3:7", "7:6", "6:7", "7:3"],
    "answer": "6:7"
  },
  {
    "number": 13,
    "question": "Today is Monday. After 61 days it will be:",
    "options": ["Wednesday", "Saturday", "Tuesday", "Thursday"],
    "answer": "Saturday"
  },
  {
    "number": 14,
    "question": "Find odd man out: 8, 27, 64, 100, 125, 216, 343",
    "options": ["125", "27", "100", "343"],
    "answer": "100"
  },
  {
    "number": 15,
    "question": "The following words have a certain relation to each other. Select the pair which has the relationship: Distance : mile",
    "options": ["liquid: litre", "bushel: corn", "weight: scale", "fame: television"],
    "answer": "liquid: litre"
  },
  {
    "number": 16,
    "question": "Choose the word which best expresses the meaning of the given word: Infrequent",
    "options": ["never", "usual", "rare", "sometimes"],
    "answer": "rare"
  },
  {
    "number": 17,
    "question": "Choose the word which is the exact opposite of the given word: Confess",
    "options": ["deny", "refuse", "contest", "contend"],
    "answer": "deny"
  },
  {
    "number": 18,
    "question": "Siya runs faster than Jiya. Lily runs faster than Siya. Jiya runs faster than Lily. If the first two statements are true, the third statement is:",
    "options": ["true", "false", "both true and false", "uncertain"],
    "answer": "false"
  },
  {
    "number": 19,
    "question": "Kiran walks 5 km towards east and then turns left and walks 6 km. Again he turns right and walks 9 km. Finally he turns to his right and walks 6 km. How far is he from the starting point?",
    "options": ["26 km", "21 km", "14 km", "9 km"],
    "answer": "14 km"
  },
  {
    "number": 20,
    "question": "If 20% of a = b, then b% of 20 is same as:",
    "options": ["4% of a", "5% of a", "20% of a", "none of these"],
    "answer": "4% of a"
  },
  {
    "number": 21,
    "question": "Government of India recently declared an animal as National aquatic animal, for protecting aquatic life. Identify the animal:",
    "options": ["Whale", "Crocodile", "River Dolphin", "Indian Mackerel"],
    "answer": "River Dolphin"
  },
  {
    "number": 22,
    "question": "How many genes are present in the human genome?",
    "options": ["1,00,000", "30,000", "50,000", "10,000"],
    "answer": "30,000"
  },
  {
    "number": 23,
    "question": "Joule/second is the unit of:",
    "options": ["Work", "Power", "Energy", "Force"],
    "answer": "Power"
  },
  {
    "number": 24,
    "question": "Which country performed the world's first self regulating fully artificial heart transplantation in December 2013?",
    "options": ["France", "Germany", "China", "USA"],
    "answer": "France"
  },
  {
    "number": 25,
    "question": "Find out the odd one:",
    "options": ["Zoological park", "Botanical Garden", "Seed Bank", "National Park"],
    "answer": "Seed Bank"
  },
  {
    "number": 26,
    "question": "Who invented electric battery?",
    "options": ["Thomas Alva Edison", "Isaac Newton", "Alessandro Volta", "Michael Faraday"],
    "answer": "Alessandro Volta"
  },
  {
    "number": 27,
    "question": "Which among the following is not a monosaccharide?",
    "options": ["Lactose", "Glucose", "Fructose", "Galactose"],
    "answer": "Lactose"
  },
  {
    "number": 28,
    "question": "Wind glasses of vehicles are made by:",
    "options": ["Fibre Glass", "Borosilicate Glass", "Flint Glass", "Safety Glass"],
    "answer": "Safety Glass"
  },
  {
    "number": 29,
    "question": "Fuel with highest calorific value is:",
    "options": ["Methane", "Biogas", "Hydrogen", "Petrol"],
    "answer": "Hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "number": 30,
    "question": "Lens used to rectify farsightedness:",
    "options": ["Concave", "Convex", "Cylindrical", "Biconcave"],
    "answer": "Convex"
  },
  {
    "number": 31,
    "question": "The first ISO certified police station in Kerala:",
    "options": ["Thiruvananthapuram", "Thrissur", "Ernakulam", "Kozhikkode"],
    "answer": "Ernakulam"
  },
  {
    "number": 32,
    "question": "In which year Kuriakose Elias Chavara died?",
    "options": ["1871", "1873", "1874", "1881"],
    "answer": "1871"
  },
  {
    "number": 33,
    "question": "The season of retreating monsoon:",
    "options": ["June-September", "December-February", "October-November", "March-May"],
    "answer": "October-November"
  },
  {
    "number": 34,
    "question": "In which year India became a member of ADB?",
    "options": ["1991", "1966", "1986", "1996"],
    "answer": "1966"
  },
  {
    "number": 35,
    "question": "The first woman Keralite to become a member of both Lok Sabha and Rajya Sabha:",
    "options": ["Ammu Swaminathan", "Akkamma Cheriyan", "Annie Mascarene", "Suseela Gopalan"],
    "answer": "Annie Mascarene"
  },
  {
    "number": 36,
    "question": "The author of the book 'Swaraj':",
    "options": ["Thushar Gandhi", "Aravind Kejriwal", "Bal Thackaray", "Narendra Modi"],
    "answer": "Aravind Kejriwal"
  },
  {
    "number": 37,
    "question": "'Kuruva Island' is situated in:",
    "options": ["Kabani", "Bhavani", "Pambar", "Chaliyar"],
    "answer": "Kabani"
  },
  {
    "number": 38,
    "question": "The state which has lowest sex ratio:",
    "options": ["Bihar", "Orissa", "Arunachal Pradesh", "Tripura"],
    "answer": "Arunachal Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "number": 39,
    "question": "The founder of 'Sidhashramam':",
    "options": ["Sree Narayana Guru", "Vagbhatananda", "Ayya Vaikundar", "Brahmananda Sivayogi"],
    "answer": "Vagbhatananda"
  },
  {
    "number": 40,
    "question": "Who proclaimed \"Go back to Gita\"?",
    "options": ["Dayananda Saraswathi", "Swami Vivekanandan", "Gandhiji", "Sree Ramakrishna Paramahamsan"],
    "answer": "Dayananda Saraswathi"
  },
  {
    "number": 41,
    "question": "Which country hosts World Men Hockey Tournament in 2018?",
    "options": ["Australia", "Kuwait", "India", "Newzealand"],
    "answer": "India"
  },
  {
    "number": 42,
    "question": "The social reformer who is also known as 'Pulayan Mathayi':",
    "options": ["Kumara Guru", "Sahodaran Ayyappan", "Pandit Karuppan", "Dr. Palpu"],
    "answer": "Pandit Karuppan"
  },
  {
    "number": 43,
    "question": "The river flowing between Vindhya and Satpura Ranges:",
    "options": ["Brahmaputra", "Mahanadi", "Krishna", "Narmada"],
    "answer": "Narmada"
  },
  {
    "number": 44,
    "question": "The first film released through internet:",
    "options": ["Vivah", "Munnabai MBBS", "Dhoom", "Sholay"],
    "answer": "Vivah"
  },
  {
    "number": 45,
    "question": "'In the Line of Fire' is the autobiography of:",
    "options": ["Ariel Sharon", "Saddam Hussain", "Parvez Musharraf", "Vladimir Putin"],
    "answer": "Parvez Musharraf"
  },
  {
    "number": 46,
    "question": "The World Environment Day is:",
    "options": ["May 5", "June 22", "July 10", "June 5"],
    "answer": "June 5"
  },
  {
    "number": 47,
    "question": "Hari Prasad Chaurasia is famous in which field:",
    "options": ["Tabla", "Flute", "Guitar", "Violin"],
    "answer": "Flute"
  },
  {
    "number": 48,
    "question": "Which country shares the shortest international boundary with India?",
    "options": ["Myanmar", "Nepal", "Bangladesh", "Afghanistan"],
    "answer": "Afghanistan"
  },
  {
    "number": 49,
    "question": "Soil which predominates in Sundarban Area:",
    "options": ["Alluvial soil", "Red soil", "Laterite soil", "Black soil"],
    "answer": "Alluvial soil"
  },
  {
    "number": 50,
    "question": "The first aircraft carrier of Indian Navy:",
    "options": ["INS Vikrant", "INS Tharangini", "INS Chakra", "INS Virat"],
    "answer": "INS Vikrant"
  },
  {
    "number": 51,
    "question": "'Jal Mahal' situated in:",
    "options": ["Jodhpur", "Udaipur", "Jaipur", "Raipur"],
    "answer": "Jaipur"
  },
  {
    "number": 52,
    "question": "Nautanki is the dance form of which Indian state:",
    "options": ["Manipur", "Uttar Pradesh", "Gujarat", "Punjab"],
    "answer": "Uttar Pradesh"
  },
  {
    "number": 53,
    "question": "Rajiv Gandhi Indian Institute of Management is in:",
    "options": ["New Delhi", "Dehradun", "Shillong", "Hyderabad"],
    "answer": "Shillong"
  },
  {
    "number": 54,
    "question": "Where was the 2010 Winter Olympics held?",
    "options": ["USA", "Switzerland", "Italy", "Canada"],
    "answer": "Canada"
  },
  {
    "number": 55,
    "question": "Who established Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan?",
    "options": ["P. Mithra", "Lala Hardayal", "K.M. Munshi", "Athma Ram Pandurang"],
    "answer": "K.M. Munshi"
  },
  {
    "number": 56,
    "question": "World Teachers Day is celebrated on:",
    "options": ["September 5", "October 5", "September 20", "November 5"],
    "answer": "October 5"
  },
  {
    "number": 57,
    "question": "Who won the World Chess Championship 2013?",
    "options": ["Magnus Carlsen", "Vladimir Dyokovich", "Viswanathan Anand", "P. Harikrishnan"],
    "answer": "Magnus Carlsen"
  },
  {
    "number": 58,
    "question": "Indian Prime Minister who established National Dairy Development Board:",
    "options": ["Jawaharlal Nehru", "Narasimha Rao", "Morarji Desai", "Indira Gandhi"],
    "answer": "Morarji Desai"
  },
  {
    "number": 59,
    "question": "The first cyber forensic laboratory in India:",
    "options": ["Maharashtra", "Tripura", "Andhra Pradesh", "Kerala"],
    "answer": "Kerala"
  },
  {
    "number": 60,
    "question": "Who was the first Indian woman to receive Magsaysay award?",
    "options": ["Indira Gandhi", "Captain Lakshmi Sehgal", "Vandana Shiva", "Kiran Bedi"],
    "answer": "Kiran Bedi"
  },
  {
    "number": 61,
    "question": "What is the minimum age qualification required for a candidate to be elected as a member of the Rajya Sabha?",
    "options": ["25 years", "30 years", "18 years", "35 years"],
    "answer": "30 years"
  },
  {
    "number": 62,
    "question": "Which one among the following was described by Dr. Ambedkar as the 'heart and soul' of the Constitution?",
    "options": [
      "Right to freedom of speech and expression",
      "Right to equality",
      "Right to constitutional remedies",
      "Right against exploitation"
    ],
    "answer": "Right to constitutional remedies"
  },
  {
    "number": 63,
    "question": "Who among the following can preside but cannot vote in one of the Houses of Parliament?",
    "options": [
      "Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "Deputy Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "Vice President of India",
      "Deputy Chairman of Rajya Sabha"
    ],
    "answer": "Vice President of India"
  },
  {
    "number": 64,
    "question": "The Chief Election Commissioner holds office:",
    "options": [
      "for a period of six years",
      "during the pleasure of the President",
      "for a period of five years",
      "for a period of six years or till the age of 65 years whichever is earlier"
    ],
    "answer": "for a period of six years or till the age of 65 years whichever is earlier"
  },
  {
    "number": 65,
    "question": "Who among the following was not a member of the Drafting Committee for the Constitution of India?",
    "options": [
      "T. Prakasam",
      "Alladi Krishnaswamy Iyer",
      "T.T. Krishnamachari",
      "N. Gopalaswami Iyengar"
    ],
    "answer": "T. Prakasam"
  },
  {
    "number": 66,
    "question": "The 97th amendment to the Constitution dealt with:",
    "options": [
      "The structure of Election Commission",
      "Universalising Elementary Education",
      "Anti defection",
      "The powers of Panchayati Raj institutions"
    ],
    "answer": "The powers of Panchayati Raj institutions"
  },
  {
    "number": 67,
    "question": "The age of retirement of the judges of the High Courts is:",
    "options": ["62 years", "60 years", "58 years", "65 years"],
    "answer": "62 years"
  },
  {
    "number": 68,
    "question": "The joint session of both Houses of Parliament is presided over by:",
    "options": [
      "The President",
      "The Speaker of Lok Sabha",
      "Chairman of Rajya Sabha",
      "The Prime Minister"
    ],
    "answer": "The Speaker of Lok Sabha"
  },
  {
    "number": 69,
    "question": "While General Emergency is in operation, the duration of Lok Sabha can be extended for a period of:",
    "options": [
      "six months only",
      "six months at a time",
      "one year only",
      "one year at a time"
    ],
    "answer": "one year at a time"
  },
  {
    "number": 70,
    "question": "Under which of the following articles of the Indian Constitution provisions for the creation and abolition of Legislative Councils in states are made?",
    "options": ["168", "169", "170", "171"],
    "answer": "169"
  },
  {
    "number": 71,
    "question": "Which part of the following sentence is incorrect? The film that I watched yesterday is about a young lady who was a famous actress.",
    "options": ["The film", "that I watched yesterday", "is about a young lady", "who was a famous actress"],
    "answer": "who was a famous actress"
  },
  {
    "number": 72,
    "question": "The wall was _____ high that I could not reach its top.",
    "options": ["so", "very", "too", "much"],
    "answer": "so"
  },
  {
    "number": 73,
    "question": "When Sunny arrived home his children:",
    "options": ["went to sleep", "had gone to sleep", "has gone to sleep", "was going to sleep"],
    "answer": "had gone to sleep"
  },
  {
    "number": 74,
    "question": "The expression 'vox populi' means:",
    "options": ["popular hatred", "electoral verdict", "opinion poll", "popular opinion"],
    "answer": "popular opinion"
  },
  {
    "number": 75,
    "question": "Why don't you look _____ the dictionary to get the correct meaning of this word?",
    "options": ["at", "on", "up", "upon"],
    "answer": "up"
  },
  {
    "number": 76,
    "question": "The passive form of the sentence \"Her recklessness did her in.\" is:",
    "options": [
      "She is done in by her recklessness",
      "She was done in by her recklessness",
      "She has been done in by her recklessness",
      "She had been done in by her recklessness"
    ],
    "answer": "She was done in by her recklessness"
  },
  {
    "number": 77,
    "question": "Germany is _____ European country.",
    "options": ["a", "an", "the", "no article required"],
    "answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "number": 78,
    "question": "Nowadays, companies _____ and fire employees as they please.",
    "options": ["hair", "here", "hire", "hear"],
    "answer": "hire"
  },
  {
    "number": 79,
    "question": "The indirect form of the sentence \"How did you solve this problem?' the teacher asked the girl\" is:",
    "options": [
      "The teacher asked the girl how she solved that problem",
      "The teacher asked the girl how she had solved that problem",
      "The teacher asked the girl how she has solved the problem",
      "The teacher asked the girl whether she had solved that problem"
    ],
    "answer": "The teacher asked the girl how she had solved that problem"
  },
  {
    "number": 80,
    "question": "When I came to the railway station, the train had _____ left.",
    "options": ["lately", "yet", "earlier", "already"],
    "answer": "already"
  },
  {
    "number": 81,
    "question": "National Rural Employment Guarantee Act was passed in the year:",
    "options": ["2001", "2003", "2005", "2007"],
    "answer": "2005"
  },
  {
    "number": 82,
    "question": "Aam Admi Bima Yojana is a programme meant for:",
    "options": [
      "Housing for slum dwellers",
      "Housing for Rural Landless Poor",
      "Insurance for SC/ST",
      "Insurance for Rural Landless Poor"
    ],
    "answer": "Insurance for Rural Landless Poor"
  },
  {
    "number": 83,
    "question": "'Slum Free India' is an objective of:",
    "options": [
      "Indira Awas Yojana",
      "Rajiv Awas Yojana",
      "Samagra Awas Yojana",
      "Bharath Nirman"
    ],
    "answer": "Rajiv Awas Yojana"
  },
  {
    "number": 84,
    "question": "The programme implemented for the empowerment of women according to National Education Policy:",
    "options": [
      "Indira Mahila Yojana",
      "Mahila Samakhya",
      "Rashtriya Mahila Khosh",
      "Mahila Samridhi Yojana"
    ],
    "answer": "Mahila Samakhya"
  },
  {
    "number": 85,
    "question": "Food for Work Programme was started in the year:",
    "options": ["1957", "1974", "1977", "1979"],
    "answer": "1977"
  },
  {
    "number": 86,
    "question": "PURA stands for:",
    "options": [
      "Poverty reduction in Urban and Rural Areas",
      "Provision of Urban Amenities in Rural Areas",
      "Provision of electricity in Urban and Rural Areas",
      "Poverty and Unemployment Reduction Agency"
    ],
    "answer": "Provision of Urban Amenities in Rural Areas"
  },
  {
    "number": 87,
    "question": "Valmiki Awas Yojana is planned to provide:",
    "options": [
      "Housing for Rural landless poor",
      "Housing for Urban Landless poor",
      "Housing for Slum Inhabitants",
      "Housing for SC/ST below poverty line"
    ],
    "answer": "Housing for Slum Inhabitants"
  },
  {
    "number": 88,
    "question": "Kutir Jyoti is a welfare programme for providing:",
    "options": [
      "Housing for rural poor",
      "Electrification of houses of SC/ST",
      "Housing for SC/ST",
      "Electrification of urban slums"
    ],
    "answer": "Electrification of houses of SC/ST"
  },
  {
    "number": 89,
    "question": "Integrated Child Development Services was started in the year:",
    "options": ["1970", "1972", "1975", "1980"],
    "answer": "1975"
  },
  {
    "number": 90,
    "question": "Annapoorna is a welfare programme for:",
    "options": [
      "Providing Food for work",
      "Food security of SC/ST",
      "Food security of senior citizens",
      "Food security of disabled"
    ],
    "answer": "Food security of senior citizens"
  },
  {
    "number": 91,
    "question": "A group of four bits is known as a/an:",
    "options": ["byte", "nibble", "quartet", "octet"],
    "answer": "nibble"
  },
  {
    "number": 92,
    "question": "The Hexadecimal equivalent of the decimal number 162 is:",
    "options": ["A2", "B2", "C2", "D2"],
    "answer": "A2"
  },
  {
    "number": 93,
    "question": "Which of the following system software translate and execute high level language source code, statement by statement?",
    "options": ["Assembler", "Compiler", "Interpreter", "Operating system"],
    "answer": "Interpreter"
  },
  {
    "number": 94,
    "question": "Which of the following technology is used for exchange of data between different systems?",
    "options": [
      "Extensible markup language",
      "Hypertext markup language",
      "Dynamic Hypertext markup Language",
      "Practical Extraction and Reporting Language"
    ],
    "answer": "Extensible markup language"
  },
  {
    "number": 95,
    "question": "A java program that executes from a web page is called:",
    "options": ["Portlet", "Servlet", "Weblet", "Applet"],
    "answer": "Applet"
  },
  {
    "number": 96,
    "question": "A private computer network within an organisation or company that allows controlled access from the outside is known as:",
    "options": ["Intranet", "Extranet", "Biznet", "Firmnet"],
    "answer": "Extranet"
  },
  {
    "number": 97,
    "question": "Which is the standard protocol for sending emails across the Internet?",
    "options": [
      "Hyper Text Transfer Protocols (HTTP)",
      "Post Office Protocol (POP)",
      "Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP)",
      "Internet Message Access Protocol (IMAP)"
    ],
    "answer": "Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP)"
  },
  {
    "number": 98,
    "question": "'Software Piracy' refers to:",
    "options": [
      "Unauthorised copying of software",
      "Data theft by means of software",
      "Spreading of malicious software",
      "Denial of service attack on a server"
    ],
    "answer": "Unauthorised copying of software"
  },
  {
    "number": 99,
    "question": "Which of the following terms is not associated with the cyber crime of attempting to acquire information by masquerading as a trustworthy entity?",
    "options": ["Whaling", "Clone phishing", "Bait phishing", "Spear phishing"],
    "answer": "Bait phishing"
  },
  {
    "number": 100,
    "question": "Section 67 of IT Act 2000 deals with:",
    "options": [
      "Tampering of computer source documents",
      "Penalty for damage to computer, computer systems etc.",
      "Establishment of cyber appellate Tribunal",
      "Publishing of information which is obscene in electronic form"
    ],
    "answer": "Publishing of information which is obscene in electronic form"
  }
]